[
  {
    "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
    "options": [
      "Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language",
      "Home Tool Markup Language",
      "Hyperlinking Text Management Language",
      "HyperText Markup Language"
    ],
    "answer": "HyperText Markup Language"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a markup language?",
    "options": [
      "A programming language to perform calculations",
      "A language that uses tags to define the structure of content",
      "A database language",
      "A styling language for web pages"
    ],
    "answer": "A language that uses tags to define the structure of content"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term “HyperText” in HTML mean?",
    "options": [
      "Text with images",
      "Text with styles",
      "Text with clickable links",
      "Text with audio"
    ],
    "answer": "Text with clickable links"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following browsers execute HTML code?",
    "options": [
      "Google Chrome",
      "Mozilla Firefox",
      "Safari",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can a web page contain?",
    "options": [
      "Forms like login.html and register.html",
      "Images and hyperlinks",
      "Headings and paragraphs",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who maintains HTML standards?",
    "options": [
      "ISO (International Organization for Standardization)",
      "W3C (World Wide Web Consortium)",
      "IEEE",
      "ECMA"
    ],
    "answer": "W3C (World Wide Web Consortium)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the present version of HTML?",
    "options": [
      "HTML-2",
      "HTML-3",
      "HTML-4",
      "HTML-5"
    ],
    "answer": "HTML-5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which section of the HTML document contains the visible content?",
    "options": [
      "<head>",
      "<body>",
      "<html>",
      "<!DOCTYPE>"
    ],
    "answer": "<body>"
  },
  {
    "question": "HTML is mainly used for developing?",
    "options": [
      "Database",
      "Frontend (User Interface)",
      "Backend (Business Logic)",
      "Operating Systems"
    ],
    "answer": "Frontend (User Interface)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which language is used to create web pages?",
    "options": [
      "Java",
      "C++",
      "HTML",
      "Python"
    ],
    "answer": "HTML"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tag defines the root element of an HTML document?",
    "options": [
      "<root>",
      "<doc>",
      "<html>",
      "<head>"
    ],
    "answer": "<html>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created HTML?",
    "options": [
      "James Gosling",
      "Tim Berners-Lee",
      "Dennis Ritchie",
      "Bjarne Stroustrup"
    ],
    "answer": "Tim Berners-Lee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which language is commonly used for back-end development?",
    "options": [
      "Java",
      ".Net",
      "Python",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are examples of HTML Editors?",
    "options": [
      "Notepad",
      "Notepad++",
      "Editplus",
      "SublimeText",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are examples of IDEs used for web development?",
    "options": [
      "WebStorm",
      "Visual Studio Code",
      "Dreamweaver",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
   {
    "question": "What is the range of heading tags in HTML?",
    "options": [
      "<h1> to <h5>",
      "<h1> to <h4>",
      "<h1> to <h6>",
      "<h1> to <h3>"
    ],
    "answer": "<h1> to <h6>"
  },
  {
    "question": "In HTML, data inside a <p> tag are:",
    "options": [
      "Preserved exactly as typed",
      "Ignored and collapsed into a single space",
      "Converted into tabs",
      "Converted into underscores"
    ],
    "answer": "Ignored and collapsed into a single space"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are Unpaired tags?",
    "options": [
      "<hr>",
      "<br>",
      "<img>",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "In HTML, text inside the <pre> tag:",
    "options": [
      "Collapses multiple spaces into one",
      "Preserves all spaces and line breaks exactly as typed",
      "Converts all text to uppercase",
      "Ignores spaces and line breaks"
    ],
    "answer": "Preserves all spaces and line breaks exactly as typed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are inline HTML elements?",
    "options": [
      "<b>",
      "<q>",
      "<small>",
      "<span>",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about <span>?",
    "options": [
      "It displays text exactly as typed and preserves all spaces and line breaks",
      "It represents a portion of text inside a paragraph.",
      "It automatically creates a new paragraph",
      "It is a block-level element that starts on a new line"
    ],
    "answer": "It represents a portion of text inside a paragraph."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are block-level HTML elements?",
    "options": [
      "<p>",
      "<pre>",
      "<h1>",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are paired tags?",
    "options": [
      "<sup>",
      "<i>",
      "<mark>",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Every HTML element contains which of the following?",
    "options": [
      "Start / Opening Tag – marks the beginning of an element",
      "End / Closing Tag – marks the end of an element",
      "Content – the text or data contained within the element",
      "Attribute – provides extra information to the element",
      "Value – the value assigned to the attribute",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  }
]
